<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vojtech Kejzlar</title>
    <link>http://www.kejzlar.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vojtech Kejzlar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://www.kejzlar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.kejzlar.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kejzlar.com/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Vojtech (Vojta) Kejzlar. I am a data scientist, an academic, and a science educator. My work focuses on Bayesian data analysis, predictive modeling, and uncertainty quantification in the context of machine learning. I build statistical and machine learning tools to solve problems in physical sciences and create innovative resources for data science literacy. I am currently an Assistant Professor of Statistics in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at Skidmore College in Saratoga Springs, New York.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.kejzlar.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kejzlar.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Here are projects that I have been working on during the past couple of years. They are a mix of Bayesian data analysis, machine learning modeling, and data science education. Take a look at the list of my publications and my GitHub to see the fruits of this labor.
Bayesian Mining of Nuclear Mass DataLink to headingThe mass, or binding energy, is the basic property of the atomic nucleus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://www.kejzlar.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.kejzlar.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Vojtech Kejzlar, Tapabrata Maiti (2023). Variational Inference With Vine Copulas: an Efficient Approach for Bayesian Computer Model Calibration. Statistics and Computing. arXiv
Vojtech Kejzlar, Jingchen Hu (2023). Introducing Variational Inference in Statistics and Data Science Curriculum. The American Statistician. arXiv
Vojtech Kejzlar, Shrijita Bhattacharya, Mookyong Son, Tapabrata Maiti (2022). Black Box Variational Bayesian Model Averaging. The American Statistician. arXiv
Vojtech Kejzlar, Mookyong Son, Shrijita Bhattacharya, Tapabrata Maiti (2021). A Fast and Calibrated Computer Model Emulator: an Empirical Bayes Approach.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
